### Mohd. Danish Shamim

### **Professional Summary**

An enthusiastic Web developer with 1+ year of exp. who is capable to use technical skills for the betterment of the organization. The full Stack Developer course has enhanced my proficiency in developing web applications and looking forward to working in a competitive environment that enhances overall learning. To obtain a challenging position that fully utilizes my skill and provides me with suitable opportunities to grow my technical and communication skill.

### **Experience**

React Developer Oct 2022 – Present

Teczones LLC

Noida, India

- Developing and implementing user interface components using React.js concepts and workflows such as Redux, Flux, and Webpack.
- Responsible for profiling and improving front-end performance and documenting front-end codebase.
- Troubleshooting interface software and debugging application codes.
- Monitoring and improving front-end performance.
- Documenting application changes and developing updates.

### **Full Stack Web Development Boot-Camp**

May 2022 - Oct 2022

Newton School (Remote)

Bengaluru, Karnataka

- Technical Stack Learnt: Data Structure & Algorithms, Java, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, MySQL, Nodejs.
- Participated in various coding competitions held by Newton School.
- Worked on various projects.

Technical IT Recruiter Nov 2021 – May 2022

e-Team Inc.

Client: UST Global, Cognizant

- Manage all phase of full-cycle recruiting from initial sourcing and screening through offer negotiation and placement.
- Responsible for searching and recruiting the candidates on various skills set as per the job specification.
- Extensively worked on w2 & C2C req. and provide best IT cand. to client Pre-&-Post Interview preparation & follow up.
  Technical IT Recruiter

E-Solutions Noida, India

Client: Wells Fargo, Comcast Cable

- Sourcing the consultant from various job portals like Job, Diva, Monster, LinkedIn and from internal portal.
- Maintaining regular communication with all candidates and focus on complete recruitment lifecycle.

Network Engineer Nov 2019 – Apr 2020

Vmak Research & Services

- Worked on the Different Operating system like Linux, Windows and configure the Network by CLI.
- Handle data transferring b/w multiple devices on a server.
- Use Wireshark to analyze packets and provide network troubleshooting.

## **Projects**

### Pizza-Sizza

## pizza-app

- A Platform for order the pizza and burger, it provides a way to track your order and manage them in one place.
- Tools & Technologies used: Tailwind CSS, React.js, Next.js for routing.

# Filmy-World

# Filmy-world

- Full website for watching movies and add review, it has a functionality of login and register authorized by Otp which is manage by firebase from Google.
- Tools & Technologies used: Tailwind CSS, React.js, React-Router-Dom, Firebase, APIs.

#### Education

#### Glocal University, Mirzapur Pole, Saharanpur

Jul 2015 – June 2019

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering

GPA: 6.50/10.0 2013-2015

Noida, India

**Kendriya Vidyalaya, AFS Uttar Pradesh** Senior Secondary

71%

semor secondar

/ 170

## Skills

Programming Languages: Java, JavaScript

UI/UX Design Tools: Adobe Photoshop, Figma, Sketch, and Corel Draw.

Web Technologies: HTML, CSS/Tailwind CSS, Material UI, jQuery, React, Redux, Express.js, EJS, and NextJs.

Miscellaneous: MySQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, Nodejs, RESTful APIs and DSA.